# Marissa du Bois

Programmer Analyst at Software Planning

marissa@galacticsoft.net

## Summary

I am passionate about software development in all of it's facets. I have been programming both personally and professionally for over 15 years. I am seeking a position with a company that will allow me to utilize my current skills while providing the opportunity to expand my abilities and further my career.

# Experience

## Programmer Analyst at Software Planning

July 2010 - Present (4 years 5 months)

Responsible for designing, developing, testing and debugging features for our winery management software as requested by customers or supervisors. Optimizes code and TSQL queries to improve performance and resolve bugs. Manages SQL server and Windows Servers deployed to customers. Respond to telephone calls, and email requests for technical support. Documents, tracks and monitors issues to ensure a timely resolution. Consults with customers to develop new features or software depending on need.

## Help Desk Technician at SanMar

August 2008 - April 2010 (1 year 9 months)

Provide support to end users on a variety of issues. Identify, research, and resolve technical problems. Respond to telephone calls, email and personnel requests for technical support. Documents, tracks and monitors issues to ensure a timely resolution. Creates and Maintains Macros, Logon and WMI scripts in VBA, VBS and Batch files. Develops, Maintains and Supports, various tools and applications used by the Help Desk and other departments. Also, supports the intranet content management system Typo3. Creates and maintains content and tools for the IT department intranet page with Typo3 and AJAX. Supports departmental administrators who also manage intranet content. Helps users resolve issues with content, creates Typo3 user accounts, sets permissions and responds to questions specific to the Typo3 environment. Setup, deployed and supported Avaya PBX analog, digital, software, and IP based phone technologies.

#### **Operations Specialist at SanMar**

January 2006 - August 2008 (2 years 8 months)

Work with management to implement call center related policies. Use Visual Basic for Applications to create Excel macros for reporting and automation. Designed and implemented a call center attendance tracking system within excel, using VBA and Microsoft Access. Responsible for database maintenance, training supervisors on calendar use, automated report monitoring and maintenance. Support supervisors with questions related to call center software. Also general administrative assistant duties, tracking attendance, updating agent stats, approving time-off requests, filing, and data entry.

### Sales Fax Associate at SanMar

July 2004 - January 2006 (1 year 7 months)

Provided excellent customer service by phone as well as e-mail. Entered faxed orders and communicated with customers regarding any questions or changes to their orders.

## Warehouse Temp at SanMar

April 2004 - July 2004 (4 months)

Worked as a temporary worker, stocked bins with product, and also pulled product to be delivered to customers.

## **Projects**

### **Azmyth**

January 2010 to Present

Members: Marissa du Bois

Azmyth is a generic game framework used to create flexible RPG and adventure style games. It can be used to produce procedurally generate height maps and temperature maps that can be rendered in a variety of ways. It uses QuadTrees and Perlin Noise to generate psuedo-infinite maps in real time. It can also be configured to use different noise algorithms such as Simplex and Value noise. Demos are available in WinForms/GDI+ and XNA.

#### **GalacticSoft Finance**

July 2013 to Present

Members:Marissa du Bois

GalacticSoft Finance is a multi-user personal finanace appliaction. Users can share bank accounts and keep track of personal financial trasactions. Hosted on my personal LAMP server and written in HTML/CSS/JavaScript/mySQL/PHP.

#### VinBalance

July 2010 to Present

Members: Marissa du Bois, Larry Nelson, Jodi Emtman

VinBalance is complete winery management software. From crush to customer, VinBalance handles the complete winery business cycle. Comprehensive accounts receivable, accounts payable, inventory, distribution, tax reporting, payroll, general ledger, tasting room point of sale and wine club features bring all of your records into a controlled and accurate system.

#### SanMar Calendar

January 2006 to Present

Members: Marissa du Bois

SanMar Calendar was a call center attendance tracking and reporting tool used to manage all daily functions of the CCC Administration department. It tracked attendance and phone statistics for a call center of over 400 employees and was eventually adopted by other departments. It was written in Excel VBA and MS Access.

## Diku MUD Area Editor

## January 2003 to January 2005

#### Members: Marissa du Bois

DIKU MUD Area Editor is an application used to create Diku/Magma MUD compatible area files. The interface replicates the experience of a MUD but offers graphical editors for areas, rooms, mobiles, items, scripts, shops and quests. Diku Edit was written using C++ and MFC.

# Skills & Expertise

C++

**C**#

 $\mathbf{C}$ 

**PHP** 

HTML

JavaScript

.NET

**T-SQL Stored Procedures** 

T-SQL

**MySQL** 

LAMP

Linux

Windows

**VBA** 

**MFC** 

**XML** 

**Microsoft Office** 

**Call Center Administration** 

**Software Development** 

**Programming** 

**Visual Studio** 

**Github** 

MonoDevelop

**XAML** 

**CSS** 

**XNA** 

**Telecommunications** 

**Troubleshooting** 

**Problem Solving** 

Mac OS

## Education

## **Bellevue College**

Continuing Education, Computer Science, 2000 - 2002

## Mt. Si Highschool

High School, 1996 - 2000

Activities and Societies: FBLA, Science Team, Knowledge Bowl.

# Interests

Software Development, Science, Computers & Technology, Procedural Content Generation.

# Marissa du Bois

Programmer Analyst at Software Planning

marissa@galacticsoft.net



Contact Marissa on LinkedIn